啊，巴黎——世界上最浪漫的城市。
Ah, Paris, the most romantic city in the world.
这里应有尽有。
This place has got it all.
美食、高雅文化，还有最重要的，精美绝伦的建筑。
Fine foods, high culture, and most importantly, exquisite buildings.
是的，一座城市能赢得这样的声誉，绝非偶然。
Yes, a city doesn't get a reputation like this for nothing, you know.
无可挑剔。
It's unblenmished.
抱歉，我刚才说到哪儿了？
Sorry, where was I?
哦，对，徜徉在那些纪念碑和镀金雕塑之间，
Oh, yes, among the monuments and gilded sculptures,
真的会让人流连忘返。
you can really lose yourself.
那又是什么，各位？不好意思。
What is that again, guys? Sorry.
这东西怎么混进我的稿子里了？
What is this doing in my script?
让我查一下笔记，稍等。
Let me just check my notes a minute. Hang on.
哦，好吧。
Oh, okay.
这就是蒙帕纳斯大厦。
This is the Tormon Panass.
它是巴黎有史以来建造的第一栋摩天大楼，
It was the first skyscraper ever built in Paris,
而且体量庞大。
and it's a whopper.
楼高210米，
It's 210 m high
在巴黎最具历史底蕴的街区之一，
and offers 120,000 m of office space
提供了12万平方米的办公空间。
in one of Paris's most historic neighborhoods.
而当地人对它恨之入骨。
And the locals hate it.
事实上，他们是如此厌恶它，
In fact, they hate it so much
以至于就在它竣工后短短几年，
just a few years after it was completed,
一部禁止再建类似建筑的
a law was passed banning anything
法律便应声落地。
like it from ever being built again.
不过幸运的是，目前有一个计划正在推进，
But fortunately, a plan is underway
要把它从"歌剧魅影"
to transform it from the Phantom of the Opera
变成"舞会皇后"。
into the Bell of the Ball.
这个计划嘛，就是——让它隐形。
That plan, well, they're going to make it invisible.
欧洲其实并不热衷于摩天大楼。
Europe doesn't really do skyscrapers.
事实上，纽约一座城市的摩天大楼，
In fact, there are more in New York City
就比整个欧洲大陆加起来还要多。
than there are across the entire European continent.
没有哪座城市比巴黎更能说明这一点——
There's no city that better displays this than Paris,
这座城市与高层建筑之间，有着一段颇为纠结的历史。
which has a rather complicated history with tall buildings.
这段历史，就从蒙帕纳斯大厦说起。
That story starts here at the Tormon Panass.
这栋楼引发的强烈反弹是如此猛烈，
The blowback from this block was so strong
以至于1977年——仅在它竣工四年后——
that in 1977, just 4 years after it was completed,
法国总统瓦勒里·吉斯卡尔·德斯坦颁布了一道禁令，
French President Jagard Stang introduced a ban
禁止在巴黎市中心建造任何超过25米的建筑。
on building anything over 25 m in the center of Paris.
这道禁令持续了33年才被废除，
that lasted 33 years before being repealed
禁令废除后，恰好有时间启动"三角塔楼"的建设——
which left just enough time to start work on this the tour triangler
然而所有人随即又发现同样讨厌它，
before everyone decided they hated that as well
于是2023年，禁令再度恢复。
and in 2023 the ban was put back in place
在距市中心9公里、
you will find plenty of skyscrapers here in Lafon
外环路之外的城市中央商务区拉德芳斯，
the city's central business district
你倒是能看到不少摩天大楼。
9 km away from the city center beyond the outer ring road
环顾四周，
and looking around
你就能明白巴黎人为何如此执着地对摩天大楼说"不"了。
you can see why Parisians are so keen on saying no to skyscrapers
世界上很少有其他大城市
there are a few other major cities anywhere in the world
能保持如此统一的建筑风格，
that have kept such a uniform architectural style
而这正是赋予巴黎那种独特气质的关键所在。
which is key to giving Paris its devivver
但那是今天的故事。
but that's today
回到二十世纪五十年代，情形则截然不同——
back in the 1950s things were very different
这座城市破败、陈旧，
the city was rundown shabby
即便在最好的年景，也难以满足现实需求。
and even at its best was hardly fit for purpose
但这不是唯一的问题。
but that's not the only thing
同样跟不上时代的，
that's not fit for purpose
还有我们获取新闻的方式。
you could also say that about the way we get our news
不知道你们怎么想，
I don't know about you
但我发现自己有时很容易一边漫无目的地刷社交媒体，
but I find it's easy to sometimes get your news
新闻就这么顺带"刷"完了。
by just doom scrolling through social media
但这可不好。
but that's no good
我们获取信息的方式正变得越来越偏颇，
the way we consume information is getting increasingly partisan
误导信息和假新闻已经普遍到令人忧虑的程度，
with misinformation and fake news becoming scarily common,
尤其随着人工智能的兴起，情况更加严峻。
especially with the rise of AI.
这也是我为什么超过一年来一直享受与直箭新闻合作的重要原因之一。
And that's a huge part
of why I've loved working with Straight Arrow News
这也是我为什么超过一年来一直享受与直箭新闻合作的重要原因之一。
for over a year now.
你们可能已经听我提过好几次了——
You've probably heard me mention a few times
它之所以与其他新闻应用不同，
how it's different to other news apps,
是因为它汇聚了来自政治光谱两端
because it brings you reporting from a wide range of media outlets
各类媒体机构的报道。
on both sides of the political divide.
但还有一个真正关键的优势：
But there's a really crucial benefit
无论你偏左、偏右，还是中间派，
because whether you're on the left, the right, or somewhere in between,
你很可能都因为编辑立场的偏见而错过了重要报道。
the chances are you're missing important stories because of editorial bias.
直箭新闻有一个叫"媒体盲点"的功能，
Stratar News has a feature called Media Miss,
它覆盖大量新闻事件，
which reports on a huge range of stories
并分析哪些媒体在报道、哪些没有报道。
and analyzes who else is or isn't covering them.
说真的，你现在随便搜一条时事新闻，
Honestly, go and search any story that's happening right now,
它都会给出一个评分，
and they'll give you a score
告诉你哪些媒体报道过多、哪些严重缺席。
showing you who's under or over reporting on the issue.
亲眼看到我们因活在信息茧房里错过了多少，
It's amazing to see how much we can miss
真的让人大开眼界。
from being in our echo chambers.
凭借来自"各方媒体"的认证平衡评级，
With a certified balance rating from All Sides Media,
直箭新闻正在将信任重新带回新闻业，
Straight Hour News is putting the trust back into journalism,
这对像我一样
which is great if, like me,
更想自己判断、
you're interested in making up your own mind about things
而不是被人告诉该怎么想的人来说，真的是太棒了。
rather than being told what to think.
如果你想要一个能让你看清全貌的新闻来源，
If you want a news source that gives it to you straight,
就扫描屏幕上的二维码，
then download the Straight Arrow News app
下载直箭新闻吧。
using the QR code on screen.
完全免费，
It's completely free,
而且支持一下我们的视频赞助商，
and you'll be massively helping us by taking the time
对我们也是莫大的鼓励。
to go and check out one of our video sponsors.
好了，让我们回到巴黎。
Now, let's get back to Perry.
随着一个新世界从二战的废墟中渐渐重建，
As a new world began to emerge
新的生活与工作方式也随之涌现。
from the wreckage of the Second World War,
so did new ways of living and working.
巴黎那些优雅的公寓和数不尽的纪念碑，远算不上什么优势。
Paris's elegant apartments and endless monuments were far from an asset.
它们恰恰说明，
They were a sign of a city
这座城市在某种程度上被困在了过去。
that was kind of stuck in the past.
与此同时，伦敦、纽约等地
Elsewhere, places like London and New York
正在建造适应新经济需求的现代办公室。
were building modern offices
fit for the demands of the new economy.
而巴黎依然是一座作坊与工作室的
But Paris was still a city of workshops and studios,
城市，正悄悄地被时代抛下。
and it was beginning to get left behind.
巴黎在很大程度上以手工艺为根基，
Paris is very much about uh artisal crafts
这一传统可以追溯至中世纪。
which is a long history
that goes back to the medieval period.
但到了六十年代，去中心化的浪潮开始涌动，
But so in the 60s you have the move to decentralize
这与战后重建的大背景也密切相关。
and that's something that's happening
um in the wake of the war as well.
想想马歇尔计划，
So if you think of the Marshall plan
以及战后重建的重心——
and what's happening in terms of reconstruction after the war,
它并不一定落在巴黎。
it's not necessarily focused on Paris.
而是集中在法国的其他地区。
It's focused on other parts of the country.
>> 于是，参议员兼地区长官埃德加·皮萨尼登场了。
>> Enter Senator and State Prefect Edgar Bazani.
他希望在市中心打造一个现代化的目的地，
He wanted to create a modern destination
把办公族重新吸引回巴黎，
in the heart of the city that would attract office workers back into Paris
并向世界证明这座城市有能力与其他全球大都市一较高下。
and show that it was capable of competing with other major global cities.
他选中的地方，就是这里——蒙帕纳斯。
The place he chose was this Mont Panas.
几乎没有哪个地方
Now, few places could have better illustrated
比这个充满传奇色彩的街区，
the transformation from old to new
更能诠释新旧之间的嬗变了。
as this storied neighborhood.
这片区域因供奉希腊文艺女神的圣地而得名，
The area was named after the home for Greek muses
曾是艺术家们钟爱的聚集之所——
and had once been a favorite haunt of artists
他们只需几个子儿，便能在附近的咖啡馆里租一张桌子。
who would rent tables in the nearby caferies for a few teams.
据说，有些餐厅的墙壁上曾贴满了
The walls of Laurata were once decorated with sketches
艺术家们以画换餐的即兴素描。
by penalist artists in lie of payments.
>> 要想象一下，
>> You know, you have to imagine
蒙帕纳斯曾经是一个文学艺术的核心地带。
like Mopas was went from
um a literary artistic center.
二十世纪二三十年代，所有伟大的艺术家都汇聚于此。
We have all the great artists there um in the the 1920s and 30s.
后来它慢慢演变成了爵士乐的地盘，
It becomes like a jazz
多了几分说不清、道不明的颓废气息。
maybe a little bit more of a seedy uh element.
于是就有了一股推力，
So there is this push
想要清理掉这些所谓的贫困地带，
to try to clean up these, if you will,
用某种现代的东西来填充它。
poorer areas and infuse it with something that's modern.
>> 这片区域的核心，是蒙帕纳斯火车站——你可能从某张著名的历史照片认出了它。
>> At its center was the G manassess, which you may recognize from this.
但在二十世纪五十年代，
But in the 1950s,
这座车站为这片区域带来的是截然不同的人群：上班族。
the station was bringing a very different crowd into the area.
Commuters.
每天有五万人和几只猫涌入这个街区，
Every day 50,000 people and a few cats poured into the neighborhood,
而那座宏伟的老建筑已经不堪重负。
and the grand old building was struggling to keep up.
对皮萨尼来说，这正是一个清除旧物、让新鲜空气吹入城市的机会。
For Pasani, this was an opportunity
to clear out the old
对皮萨尼来说，这正是一个清除旧物、让新鲜空气吹入城市的机会。
and let fresh air into the city.
1959年，他公布了缅因-蒙帕纳斯计划，
In 1959, he unveiled the main Montanas plan,
一个分四期建设的
a vast new district to be built
庞大新城区方案。
in four separate phases.
第一期将在车站两侧各建一栋新的住宅楼。
Phase one would see two new housing blocks built either side of the station.
第三期将建造一座购物中心
Phase three would see the creation of a shopping mall
以及至关重要的摩天大楼，
and the all-important skyscraper,
而车站本身则将在第四期进行改造。
while the station itself would get a redevelopment under phase 4.
到1966年，车站和住宅已相继竣工。
By 1966, the station and housing were complete.
但那栋新摩天大楼，
But the new skyscraper,
不仅是整个计划中争议最大的部分，
as well as being the most controversial aspect of the plan,
也被证明是难度最高的。
was proving to be the most difficult.
如今建一栋摩天大楼固然是挑战，
Now, building a skyscraper today is challenging,
但我们多少认为这是可以做到的事。
but we kind of take for granted
that it is possible.
然而当缅因-蒙帕纳斯计划
But when the main panass plan
在1959年被构想出来时，
was dreamed up in 1959,
这一切远没有这么理所当然。
that was far from guaranteed.
这个开发项目由法国政府主导，
The development was being led by the French government,
而政府在建造如此规模建筑方面毫无经验。
which had no experience constructing such a huge building.
而且不只是工程技术是新的。
And it wasn't just the engineering that was new.
支撑这一切得以实现的经济逻辑，同样是全新的。
So were the economics that made this possible.
为了找到解决方案，他们求助于一位美国房地产开发商——怀·塔特尔（Wy Tuttle）。
For the solution, they turned to an American real estate developer, Wy Tuttle.
最初的方案是建一座150米高的塔楼，
The initial plan was for a 150 m tower
周围配以购物中心
surrounded by a shopping mall
和一栋较小的办公楼。
and a smaller office block.
但负责开发的国有公司
But the stateowned company in charge of the development
始终难以筹集到所需的6500万法郎建设资金。
struggled to find the 65 million Franks
needed to cover the construction.
在塔特尔的主导下，
Under Tuttle,
塔楼的设计高度又增加了60米，
the plans for the tower grew another 60 m,
将建筑推升至令人咋舌的59层。
bringing the building to a staggering 59 stories.
更多的建筑面积意味着更多的租户，
Extra space meant more tenants,
这让塔特尔得以筹措到
enabling Tuttle to generate the finance
足够的资金来覆盖建设成本。
to cover the build.
1970年，
In 1970,
在计划首次提出11年之后，
11 years after the plan was first drawn up,
施工正式启动。
construction began.
但尽管商业方案已经理顺，
But while the business case had been resolved,
塔特尔的工程团队
Tuttles's engineers still had huge problems
仍面临重重难关。
to overcome.
这是为塔楼建设划定的施工场地。
This is the site laid out for the construction of the tower.
而这些，
And these are the metro lines
是紧贴地表之下穿行的地铁线路。
that run just beneath the surface.
其中有一条——6号线——
One in particular, line
直接从塔楼地基的正下方穿过。
six, runs directly under the tower's footprint.
这栋摩天大楼的巨大竖向荷载
The enormous weight of this skyscraper
加上松软的地基土质，
and the soft soil meant
意味着若将桩基布置在6号线两侧，
that placing it around the line
土体便会不均匀沉降，
would cause the soil to subside
隧道随之坍塌。
and the tunnel to collapse.
唯一的解决方案，
The only way of avoiding this
是将这座重达12.2万吨的建筑
was to build the 122,000 ton structure
直接建在地铁线的正上方，
directly over the metro line
并确保两侧受力均衡对称。
and spread the weight evenly on each side.
为此，隧道本身必须首先得到加固。
To do that, the tunnel would obviously need to be reinforced.
工人们在铁轨两侧浇筑了钢筋混凝土挡墙，
Concrete walls were constructed on either side of the rail tracks,
其强度足以保护隧道
strong enough to protect the tunnel
并承受部分上部结构荷载。
and bear some of the building load.
隧道顶板上方安装了四根混凝土横梁以提升顶板刚度，
Above, four concrete beams were installed to strengthen the roof,
每根可承受4万吨的荷载。
capable of taking 40,000 tons of weight.
桩基从隧道两侧打入地下，为建筑提供竖向支撑，
Piles were sunk either side of this to secure the building's foundation,
但隧道下方的土层
but the soil beneath the tunnel
又带来了新的麻烦。
threw up further problems.
这片区域历史上曾被大量开采，
This area had historically been used for quarrying,
地下遗留了许多松散的空洞区域。
leaving the subs soil with large, loosely packed areas of dirt.
因此，桩基
The piles
必须穿透极深的地层——
therefore needed to be dug down to an incredible depth,
深达60米，几乎是楼高的三分之一——
60 m,
才能抵达更为稳定的
nearly a third of the height of the building,
承载力黏土层。
all to reach a more stable stratum of clay.
最终，56根桩基被打入这片土地，
56 piles were dug into the Mana soil in total
消耗了数量惊人的混凝土。
using an incredible volume of concrete.
光是桩基就用去了1.2万立方米的混凝土，
12,000 cubic meters of it were used to fill the piles,
略超整栋建筑
just over a quarter
混凝土总用量的四分之一。
of the total volume of concrete used in the entire building.
面对这种新型结构体系，
For this new type of structure,
塔特尔的团队采用了一种全新的建造方式。
Tuttles's team turned to a new type of construction.
其核心是围绕一个钢筋混凝土核心筒
It involves designing the building
来组织整栋建筑，
around a concrete core
核心筒内布置楼梯、电梯及各类设备管井。
containing space for stairs, lifts, and surfaces.
核心筒外围则是支撑各层楼板的钢结构上部框架。
Around this stands a steel superructure holding the building's floor plates.
最后，外墙围护体系附着其上。
Then last of all, the cladding is added.
如今，几乎每一栋新建建筑都采用这种结构体系。
Now today, nearly every new building is constructed using this method.
但在当时，
But at the time,
这里运用了一项相对较新的技术——
it made use of a relatively new technique
滑模施工法。
called slip forming.
这项技术最初于二十世纪初在美国发展起来，
It had been developed in the US
主要用于建造筒仓等农业构筑物。
in the early 20th century
to build agricultural structures like silos.
但到了二十世纪六十年代，它已开始广泛应用于高层建筑施工。
But by the 1960s, it was being used in high-rise buildings.
其原理是：先制作一套模具，然后持续不断地向其中浇注混凝土。
It works by constructing a mold which concrete is continuously poured into.
当下层混凝土达到初凝强度后，
As the lower layers set,
液压千斤顶将模具整体顶升，
hydraulic jacks push the mold up,
建筑就这样节节攀升。
creating a continuously growing building.
滑模施工法最大的优势之一，正是施工速度。
Now, one of the biggest benefits of slip form construction is the speed.
蒙帕纳斯大厦的核心筒24小时不间断施工，
The core of the torm pan was under construction 24/7,
每天以约30厘米的速度向上生长。
growing at a rate of around 30 cm every day.
到1973年，大厦已接近竣工，
By 1973, the tower was nearing completion,
但在地面之下，
but down at ground level,
人们的心意早已确定。
mines were already made up.
>> 蒙帕纳斯大厦本应代表
>> The tormon paness was supposed to represent
一个崭新的、充满活力的巴黎，
a new vital Paris
从那座烟熏火燎的老城中昂然崛起。
rising up out of the smoky old-fashioned city.
但问题在于，
But there was a problem.
所有人都相当喜欢那座烟熏火燎的老城。
Everyone quite liked the smoky old-fashioned city.
>> 即便到今天，这依然是一座令人叹为观止的匀质城市。
>> Even today, it's an incredibly homogeneous city.
想象一下，巴黎的建筑主体大量使用石灰岩——
Imagine Paris is created largely of limestone.
就地取材的本地石灰岩。
It's local limestone.
于是你看到了一座"宫殿之城"的形象，
So you get that idea of the palace city
材料高度统一，
with a uniformity of materials
而这种统一性正是奥斯曼男爵着力规范的。
which is something that Houseman is kind of regulating.
立面高度高度一致，
There's a uniformity of facades.
一切都呈现出那种匀质而统一的肌理。
Everything is is that that homogeneous kind of uh structure.
而这栋楼，恰恰是这一切的对立面。
And here we have the antithesis.
它相当阴沉——大面积的深色玻璃幕墙，一个整体式的巨型方块。
We have something that's quite dark with darkened glass that is a mono block.
我还没遇到过一个喜欢它的巴黎人。
I don't think I've met one Parian that likes it.
如果你听过这个故事，那也不奇怪——
Stop us if you've heard this one before,
巴黎的美学风貌，
but Paris owes much of its aesthetic
在很大程度上要归功于这位男士：奥斯曼男爵。
to this man, Baron Osman.
汲取伦敦摄政街的灵感，
Drawing inspiration from London's Regent Streets,
奥斯曼在1853年至1870年间对巴黎进行了大规模改造，
Osman extensively remodeled Paris between 1853 and 1870,
将其从一座以木结构为主的中世纪城市，
transforming it from a medieval city of timber frame buildings
蜕变为我们今天所见的新古典主义风貌。
into the neocclassical style we will see today.
这一遗产最显著的体现，是城市中那些笔直宽阔的林荫大道，
The most visible legacy of this are the city's long straight boulevards
以及那种标志性的公寓楼——
and the apartment block,
六至七层，奶油色石灰岩外墙，
a six or sevenstory building in cream limestone
底层商业，顶覆
with commercial space at the bottom
灰色孟莎屋顶。
and a gray mansard roof.
这使得整座城市拥有相当统一的建筑高度，
It gives the whole city a fairly uniform building height
营造出一种特定的城市尺度感，
which creates a sense of scale
而那座塔楼对此造成了严重的破坏。
that the tower fell well foul of.
这里的建筑高度上限
You have a scale that goes from
大约在30到31米，
scale limits are around 30 31
最高也就到37米。
and then they go up to 37 m.
而这栋楼，高达210米。
And here we've got a building that goes up to 210 m tall.
它就这样突兀地矗立在那里。
I mean it's just it sticks out.
从城市尺度来看，它实在过于激进了。
So in terms of its scale, it's just it's just radical.
它就像一座纪念碑，
It's like a stella,
对吧？它的存在，就是要让你
right? It's meant to be seen
在巴黎任何角落都能看见它。
from from wherever you are in Paris.
这是一种截然不同的城市功能理念。
just a different concept of the way in which um Paris functions.
>> 仿佛这还不够糟糕似的，
>> As if that wasn't bad enough,
由于它在一片低矮的城市肌理中
by standing so tall amid such a low-rise city,
拔地而起，这座塔楼
the tower also loomed conspicuously into view
还不可避免地闯入了巴黎许多最珍贵地标的视野廊道。
around some of Paris's most cherished landmarks.
正是这种根深蒂固的古典主义身份认同，
With such a strong classical identity,
使得任何新事物都注定显得格格不入——
it's kind of inevitable that anything new is going to stick out,
这也在某种程度上
which goes some way to explain
解释了巴黎人对新建筑历来的抵触情绪。
Parisian's historical antagonism towards new structures.
蓬皮杜中心、卢浮宫玻璃金字塔，
The Pompedu Center, the Louv Pyramids,
乃至埃菲尔铁塔，
and even the Eiffel Tower
都曾在建成之初饱受批评，最终才成为举世公认的标志性地标。
were all widely criticized before eventually becoming iconic landmarks.
我想说，也有一些人
I'd say there are preachers
为此感到遗憾——
that lament the fact
正是因为巴黎市中心没有高层建筑，
that um because there are no big towers within the center of Paris.
这座城市在某种程度上陷入了停滞。
Um that you um that it's it's stagnated.
巴黎正在成为一座游客的城市，
Paris is becomes the city of tourists,
不是吗？而这正是批评之一——
right? Um, and this is one of the critiques
回溯到奥斯曼时代，
if you go back to um, Housemen,
穷人早已被推出了这座城市。
the poor are being pushed out of the city.
>> 在2010年代，
>> In the 2010s,
不少政客和民选官员候选人
various politicians and meal hopefuls
公开呼吁将这座大厦拆除。
were openly calling for the tower to be demolished.
直到2017年，这座备受嫌弃的塔楼终于迎来了一根救命稻草。
Until in 2017, the reduced tower was thrown a lifeline.
一项全面翻新计划获得批准，
A plan was approved
方案由建筑师联合体
for a full-scale renovation
新AOM建筑事务所操刀设计。
based on a design by a consortium of architects, Newvel AOM.
这套方案竭力打破老建筑那种整体式的压迫感。
The design makes a huge effort
to break up the monolithic presence of the old building.
一条条空中花园
Bands of sky gardens
带来更多水平向的视觉层次，
create more horizontal features
以此消解原有结构那种生硬的垂直感。
than effort to break up the solid verticality of the old structure.
如今，这栋摩天大楼整天被劲风侵袭，
Today, the skyscraper is battled by strong winds
强风沿着它巨大的板状外墙呼啸而上。
that race up against its huge sailike exterior.
但新方案将这一特点化劣为优——
But the new design uses that to its advantage,
在立面上开设通风口，
creating openings in the facade
让气流自然穿行，实现建筑的被动式自然通风。
that allow this air to naturally ventilate the building.
然而真正的核心问题——
But the elephant in the room
也可以说是立面上那头大象——
or rather on the facade is the transparent glazing
正是那块透明玻璃幕墙，
which helps the tower to well blend in.
它让大厦得以……与周围融为一体。
>> 嗯，看起来确实挺漂亮的，
>> Yeah, it's so it looks pretty right.
看上去会成为蒙帕纳斯大厦一个不错的新版本。
It looks uh it looks like
但我内心深处的历史学家
it's going to be a nice version of a um of the toas,
对这次大刀阔斧的翻新还是有些质疑。
but my inner historian questions that radical makeover.
我不知道，我们会不会某天回过头来，
But I I don't know, you know,
为这栋"爱恨交加——
will we lament this, you know, iconic,
当然大多数人是恨它的"
love it or hate it, most people hate it, of course, building.
的标志性建筑感到惋惜？
它难道不能保留原有的外墙饰面，
Couldn't it have retained its uh revetment
也许在某种程度上
and maybe had some kind of at least,
保留一些基本的形式？
okay, you've got the form,
至少留住那个轮廓，
but at least that um certain elements uh kind of preserved.
再保留某些元素？真的很难说，
It's hard to say,
它看起来确实没什么吸引力，
you know, it seems pretty inattractive,
但我总觉得，
but I feel like
我们也许会失去某些更重要的东西。
maybe we might be losing something a bit more.
翻新工程预计明年正式启动，
Work's due to begin on the renovation next year,
届时大厦将被剥离
at which point
至混凝土核心筒和钢结构框架。
the tower is going to be stripped back to its core and steel frame.
此后，最大的问题来了：它会成功吗？[笑]
After that, the big question is, will it work? [snorts]
这只"丑小鸭"，会不会真的蜕变成一只优雅的天鹅？
Is the old tower the ugly duckling growing into a graceful swan?
还是说，要让巴黎人爱上这栋楼，
Or is the only way
唯一的办法
to get Parisians to love this building
就是让它彻底消失？
to make it disappear?
各位别忘了，
Remember guys,
如果你想摆脱惯常的偏见获取新闻，
if you want to get the news without the usual bias,
就点击下方链接，加入直箭新闻吧。
then get involved in Straight Hour News via the link below.
一如既往，各位，
And as always guys,
如果你喜欢这期视频，
if you enjoyed this video
想要更多来自全球最权威建筑频道的内容，
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
记得订阅B1M。
make sure you're subscribed to the B1M.